let's discuss the solution to our cache
summary quiz part one we have a 256 byte
cache with 32 byte lines and two way set
associative we have a 32-bit address we
need to know which bits are tagged index
and offset
remember to always start from the offset
bits
0 through something are the offset
which bit well 32 bytes
is 2 to the 5th bytes
so we need 5 bits to tell us which byte
we have in a line that means that we're
talking about bits 0
through 4 this is 5 bits because we
begin at 0. the index bits
are the next bits in the order of
significance so they will begin at bit
five the question is how many do we need
to determine that we need to determine
how many sets do we have in this cache
the cache has
256 bytes divided by 32 bytes this is
the number of lines
and the result is eight so we have eight
lines
it is a two-way set associative cache
so we have eight over two sets this is
four we need two bits to tell us which
set we have so it's going to be bits 5
and 6
and that means that the tag bits are
starting from 7 all the way to 31.